

# Nathanael Jones

422 Knobloch Ave, Jeffersonville, IN 47130

T: (502) 509-1177

E: nathanael.jones@gmail.com
W: http://nathanaeljones.com
W: http://computerlinguist.com

DOB: May 1990

## Objective

I believe I fulfill (and exceed) the qualifications required for your Neuroprogrammer position, and am applying for the job. I have the experience, the attitude, and the personality to fill the role well. I expect a reply at your earliest convenience.



#### Experience

#### Independent researcher of neurology and cognitive development

1997-2011

Reading the biography of Nikola Tesla at age 7 sparked my interest in the untapped potential of the human brain. Realizing I had a unique opportunity to learn more about the human brain due to my ongoing cognitive development and advanced understanding of neurology, I was able to make subtle changes to my subconscious psychology that enable me to monitor and track all my brain activity at a very low level. As an unexpected side effect, I developed the ability to instinctively know what time it is, without the need for a watch or clock of any kind. Peculiar.

I continued making changes to my neurological patterns for until 15, when it became more difficult to adjust my brain in unnatural ways due to the final stages of cognitive development having completed.

During those 8 years, however, I performed thousands of tests on myself and uncovered a great depth of understanding about my own brain processes, functions, and gained the practical ability to control them in very useful ways. While each brain is (very) unique and requires customized techniques and processes, I believe many of my discoveries could be brought to the public with the proper funding.

Some of the most basic abilities granted by these techniques could have tremendous impact on individual lives. Having advance warning of when your brain is going to start making errors, or the ability to mark a mental to-do item so you will be subconsciously reminded of it every X number of minutes regardless of distractions or circumstance.

As a side note, it was my essay on cognitive development that netted me a full scholarship for computer and electrical engineering at Speed Engineering (UofL) in 2003.

#### Freelance software architect and engineer

1996-2011

I've been designing, creating, launching, and monetizing products for a decade and a half. I launched my first successful product at age 11, which received 169,000 downloads over the next decade, remaining bug-free and stable through 8 years and 3 new operating systems. Since then, I've worked for over 70 different corporations performing difficult and impossible tasks that others had failed to accomplish. I've designed a neural network editing and monitoring system for an unnamed Israeli corporation, written satellite imagery processing systems, natural language processing and clustering prototypes, and lots of other fun stuff. I've always managed to find a way to invent new technology, pave new roads, and still get paid to do it.

I'm currently funding my year in Italy through my latest two products, <a href="www.imageresizing.net">www.imageresizing.net</a> and <a href="www.windowsgit.com">www.windowsgit.com</a>.

I'm looking for more interesting ways to spend my energy, and I'd like to return to the neuroprogramming field.

Lead software architect/engineer/security consultant/sysadmin/CIO advisor at VGR, Inc.

2004-early 2010

I worked for this (very) international organization for six years, filling around 6 job roles. I think I stayed so long because I was afraid of everything collapsing when I left, and because I enjoyed the challenge presented by so many job roles. They hired 3 replacements for me, and still had to cancel a number of projects. I regret the inconvenience my departure caused, but it was time for me to move on.

#### Education

### Speed Engineering School (Louisville, KY)

Fall 2004-Spring 2005

Full Grawemeyer Scholarship (5 years plus stipend). Studied Computer Engineering, Calculus II, etc. Kept a 4.0 GPA, dropped out before my 15<sup>th</sup> birthday to learn faster on my own, with a job.

Ivy Tech Fall 2003-Spring 2004

General education studies, advanced 3D modeling with AutoCad, basically stuff to keep my 13-year-old self out of trouble.



Skills Can perform binary and quaternary math in my head. Translating between the two is simpler than multiplication. Can't understand why it was listed as a requirement, it's rather basic.

I understand neural networks instinctively. I can execute code in my head, and can simulate over 20 different software compilers mentally. I've written 3 software compilers, and designed a number of AI systems. I can read, write, and speak over 30 computer languages including a number that are so advanced you've probably never heard of them. You want a list? You want a list.

Common LISP, C, C++, C#, Objective-C, C with Objects, Objective-C 2.o, Java, Clojure, Ruby, Lua, Javascript (all versions and variants), ActionScript (2 AND 3), PHP, Python, Tlc/tk, ASP.NET, ASP, Smalltalk, Squeak, IO, Forth, pbForth, Scheme, FFF, Bash, AppleScript, Batch, Aspect, Assembly, CoffeeScript, Erlang, F#, OCaml, Groovy, IronPython, IronRuby, loke, Jython, MATLAB, NQC, NSIS, Oz, Perl, Parrot, PostScript, Processing, Squirrel, XQuery, XSLT, and XAML.

If you have any doubts as to whether any of the above are real programming languages, please google them. If you have any doubts as to whether I understand them, please feel free to test me.

I have also intentionally left out all of the variants of BASIC despite my proficiency in all of them, for a simple reason. If you ask me to program in BASIC, QBASIC, Visual Basic, Visual Basic.NET, or any language that has "basic" in the name, you will receive pie in your face. Immediately. Or a substitute food or beverage item of my choosing.

This resume is true and exact to the best of my knowledge. I expect a reply at your convenience.

Best regards, Nathanael Jones Nathanael.jones@gmail.com